{
  "Lesson1": {
    "ID": 1,
    "Hint": "You want to Print the Working Directory to continue.",
    "Error": "Seems like you didn't type 'pwd'.  Try again.",
    "Title": "Print Working Directory",
    "Answer": "pwd",
    "Success": "/usa/california/san_francisco",
    "Branches": "",
    "Question": "Print out the current working directory.",
    "Instructions": "pwd (print working directory): This command will return the path of the directory you are currently in.",
    "Target": ""
  },
  "Lesson2": {
    "ID": 2,
    "Hint": "You need to Change the Directory to 'california' continue.",
    "Error": "Seems like you didn't type 'cd california'.  Try again.",
    "Title": "Change Directory",
    "Answer": "cd usa",
    "Success": "/usa",
    "Branches": [
      "CA",
      "NY",
      "TX"
    ],
    "Question": "Please type 'cd USA' to change directories.",
    "Instructions": "cd (change directory): This command accepts arguments in the form of file structure in order to traverse the system.  For example: '$cd california' will change your working directory to $/usa/california'.",
    "Target": "USA"
  },
  "Lesson3": {
    "ID": 3,
    "Hint": "Please Change Directories to continue.",
    "Error": "Seems like you didn't type 'cd ..'.  Try again.",
    "Title": "Change Directory",
    "Answer": "cd ..",
    "Success": "/usa/",
    "Branches": [
      "USA"
    ],
    "Question": "Please type 'cd ..' to return to $/usa/",
    "Instructions": "cd (change directory): This command accepts arguments in the form of file structure in order to traverse the system.  For example: '$cd bob' will change your working directory to $/usa/california'.",
    "Target": "Bustin' Bash"
  },
  "Lesson4": {
    "ID": 4,
    "Hint": "Please Change Directories to continue.",
    "Error": "Seems like you didn't type 'cd /california/san_francisco'.  Try again.",
    "Title": "Change Directory",
    "Answer": "cd /california/san_francisco",
    "Success": "/usa/california/san_francisco",
    "Branches": [
      "ggpark.txt, crissyfield.txt"
    ],
    "Question": "Change directories to /california/san_francisco'.",
    "Instructions": "cd (change directory): This command accepts arguments in the form of file structure in order to traverse the system.  For example: '$cd bob' will change your working directory to $/usa/california'.",
    "Target": "san_francisco"
  },
  "Lesson5": {
    "ID": 5,
    "Hint": "List the Directory.",
    "Error": "Seems like you didn't type 'ls'.  Try again.",
    "Title": "List Directory / Files",
    "Answer": "ls",
    "Success": "ggpark.txt crissyfield.txt",
    "Branches": "",
    "Question": "Please type 'ls' to display contents.",
    "Instructions": "ls (list directory / files): This command will display the contents of a directory.  For example: 'ls' will display two sub folders below.",
    "Target": ""
  },
  "Lesson6": {
    "ID": 6,
    "Hint": "Please make a directory Ohio to continue.",
    "Error": "Seems like you didn't create a directory  called Ohio!",
    "Title": "Make Directory",
    "Answer": "mkdir Ohio",
    "Success": "mkdir Ohio",
    "Branches": "",
    "Question": "Make a new directory called Ohio",
    "Instructions": "Creating directories is an integral part of using Bash. A directory is a folder on your computer that contains other folders and files. To create a new directory we use the 'mkdir' command followed by the directory name",
    "Target": ""
  },
  "Lesson7": {
    "ID": 7,
    "Hint": "Please delete the directory BustinBash to continue.",
    "Error": "Seems like you didn't delete the directory correctly.  Try again.",
    "Title": "Remove Directory",
    "Answer": "rmdir BustinBash",
    "Success": "Maybe, put a message here",
    "Branches": "",
    "Question": "Make delete the directory called BustinBash",
    "Instructions": "Next we will learn how to delete a directory using the command line. Just type mkdir BustinBash to create your directory.",
    "Target": ""
  },
  "Lesson8": {
    "id": 8,
    "Answer": "echo I love bash",
    "Error": "Seems like you didn't type the command correctly.  Try again.",
    "Hint1": "try typing something like 'echo your sentence here.'",
    "Hint2": "Sleepy....  :-o Zzzzz",
    "Instructions": "the command 'echo' is used display bash's stdoutput to the console. for example, 'bash-3.2$ echo hello out there' \n 'bash-3.2$ hello out there'",
    "Question": "please use echo to print 'I love bash' to the console",
    "Success": "I love bash",
    "Title": "bash has an echo"
  },
  "Lesson9": {
    "id": 9,
    "Answer": "$",
    "Error": "Seems like your answer is a little off. Try again.",
    "Hint1": "remember the path you $1 and $0 is the path origin.",
    "Hint2": "Sleepy....  :-o Zzzzz",
    "Instructions": "the $ is a container for the users path output. for example if we type 'cd /USA/' bash stores the arguments that were passed and logs them to '$1'. '$0' on the other hand remains unchanged since it holds the first commmand(the shell itself). the '$' is usually referred to as a path or environment variable.",
    "Question": "Use cd to navigate to '/USA/california/san_francisco' and then use echo to print your current directory",
    "Success": "/USA/california/san_francisco",
    "Title": "need more $"
  },
  "Lesson10": {
    "id": 10,
    "Answer": "echo $?",
    "Error": "Seems like your answer is a little off. Try again.",
    "Hint1": "'ls' plus 'echo' equals profit'$?'",
    "Hint2": "Sleepy....  :-o Zzzzz",
    "Instructions": "you've learned that ls can be used to display directories. but what happens if you try to display a directory that doesnt exist? it turns out, you can evaluate whether a path exists or not just by adding a '?' to the end of your '$' interpreting the path as either 0 meaning it exists, or not 0.",
    "Question": "first 'ls /USA/arnold_scwarzenneger'. then call 'echo' on '$?'.",
    "Success": "1",
    "Title": "'ls' plus 'echo' equals profit'$?'"
  },
  "Lesson11": {
    "id": 11,
    "Answer": "pushd $timesquare /USA/newyork/timesquare ",
    "Error": "Seems like your answer is a little off. Try again.",
    "Hint1": "you must either cd to the directory and pushd or specify pushd $path '/pathyouwant/'",
    "Hint2": "Sleepy....  :-o Zzzzz",
    "Instructions": "pushd is a command used to save the current working directory so that it can be recalled at a later time.",
    "Question": "Please save the path '/USA/newyork/timesquare' to timesquare using pushd'",
    "Success": "/USA/newyork/timesquare",
    "Title": "pushd"
  },
  "Lesson12": {
    "id": 12,
    "Answer": "popd",
    "Error": "Seems like your answer is a little off. Try again.",
    "Hint1": "I think you can pop this one out pretty easily.",
    "Hint2": "Sleepy....  :-o Zzzzz",
    "Instructions": "oops, we used pushd too on the same environment path too many times! now our $path is '/USA/CA/ /USA/CA/ /USA/NY/ '. to pop them out. We can use popd similarly.",
    "Question": "Please type 'popd' to pop out the last pushed directory. ",
    "Success": "/USA/CA/ /USA/NY/ ",
    "Title": "popd"
  },
  "Lesson13": {
    "id": 13,
    "Answer": "",
    "Error": "Seems like your answer is a little off. Try again.",
    "Hint1": "",
    "Hint2": "Sleepy....  :-o Zzzzz",
    "Instructions": "",
    "Question": "Please type '' ",
    "Success": "",
    "Title": "pushd"
  },
  "Lesson14": {
    "id": 14,
    "Answer": "",
    "Error": "Seems like your answer is a little off. Try again.",
    "Hint1": "",
    "Hint2": "Sleepy....  :-o Zzzzz",
    "Instructions": "",
    "Question": "Please type '' ",
    "Success": "",
    "Title": ""
  },
  "Lesson15": {
    "id": 15,
    "Answer": "",
    "Error": "Seems like your answer is a little off. Try again.",
    "Hint1": "",
    "Hint2": "Sleepy....  :-o Zzzzz",
    "Instructions": "",
    "Question": "Please type '' ",
    "Success": "",
    "Title": ""
  }
}